collegexpress.com 2019-04-10

# Privacy Policy | CollegeXpress

Thank you for visiting www.collegexpress.com ("the Site")! The Site is strongly committed to protecting your privacy. The purpose of this privacy policy is to inform users of the Site as to what information we collect and how and why we use such information. The Site is a website published and maintained by Carnegie Dartlet LLC (“Carnegie”). The terms “we”, “our” and “us” refer to Carnegie and our affiliated companies.

## 1\. Disclosure Regarding Collection and Use of Personal Data.

Through the Site, users may choose to enter personal data and information about themselves. If you decide to share personal data with us, we will ask for your consent to use that data as described in this privacy policy. This policy explains our online information collection and use practices and the choices you can make about the way we use and share such information. Please take the time to read and understand this policy so that you can understand how we use your personal data. Please note that our online data collection and use practices may differ from our practices regarding data obtained offline.

REMEMBER: IF YOU MAKE USE OF THE SITE, REGISTER WITH THE SITE, REQUEST INFORMATION THAT WE MAY OFFER OR SUBMIT DATA IN ANY WAY TO OR THROUGH THE SITE YOU AGREE TO THESE TERMS. AS WE UPDATE AND EXPAND OUR SERVICES, THIS POLICY MIGHT CHANGE, SO PLEASE REVIEW IT FROM TIME TO TIME.

## 2\. The Personal Data We Collect.

We may collect personal data and information about you through a variety of methods, such as your participation in games, quizzes, contests, chat rooms, forums or the like or other documents that you submit to us, transactions in which you may engage with us or our affiliated companies, or through visits that you may make to the Site. This policy applies to all personal data that we collect and maintain about our users, including any contact information (e.g., name and address), financial information (e.g., account and credit history), federal loan history information (e.g., loan amount, loan type, school and lender) or identifying information (e.g., social security number, date of birth) that we may obtain in connection with providing services. You may view or change your information at any time by contacting us or by signing into your account and editing your profile. In addition, you may withdraw your consent to our use of your personal data. If you do so, you may also request that we remove that data from our records and databases.

## 3\. Other Collected Information.

We also may collect certain non-personal data (i.e. generic information that does not identify you personally) when you visit any of our web pages such as the type of browser you are using (e.g., Chrome, Internet Edge), the type of operating system you are using, (e.g., Windows 10 or macOS), the IP address you are using to connect to the Site and the domain name of your Internet service provider (e.g., Spectrum or Comcast).

## 4\. How We Use Your Personal Data.

We use your personal data to provide you with products or services that you have requested, to respond to questions or communications and to get in touch with you when necessary. For example, we may use your personal data to communicate with you or to send you information that you have requested. Except as otherwise set forth on the Site, in addition, we may send to you an email offering products or services which we think you may be interested in or to ask you to participate in a survey. We do not consider any companies that are within our "family" of companies to be "third parties" for purposes of this policy. Thus, we may also share personal data provided online with companies affiliated with or owned directly or indirectly by Carnegie. Any of these companies may use and further share this data in the same ways we do. However, if we pass on personal data to a family company, we require that it protect such data in a manner that is consistent with this policy and your expressed preferences. For example, a family company may send to you an email regarding special offers and announcements about products or services that it thinks might be of interest to you. A family company may also contact you offline. If you want to opt-out from our (or a family company) using the personal data you provided in these ways, please contact us.

## 5\. Updating or Removing Your Personal Data.

Please contact us at any time to update, remove or change your personal data.

## 6\. How We Share Your Personal Data.

We will not share with third parties the personal data you provide except (a) if it is for the purpose(s) you provided it; (b) with your consent; (c) as may be required by law or as we think necessary to protect our company or others from injury (e.g. in response to a court order or subpoena, in response to a law enforcement agency request or when we believe that someone is causing (or about to cause) injury to or interference with the rights or property of another); (d) with other persons, service providers or companies with whom we contract to carry out internal site operations or our business activities (for example, sending out a product or a promotional item that you have requested on the Site); and/or (e) notifying you when we make material changes to one of our subscriber agreements or this policy. Examples of us sharing your personal data for the purposes submitted are if you participate in a third-party survey or request information from a third-party, we may provide the information provided to such third party so that they can send to you directly the information you requested. We will seek to obtain your consent at the place where the information is collected either by an "opt-in" or "opt-out" method, or by other means (such as sending to you an email). As stated above, we do not consider any companies that are within our "family" of companies to be "third parties" for purposes of this policy and may also share personal data provided online with companies affiliated with or owned directly or indirectly by Carnegie. Any of these companies may use and further share this information in the same ways we do. However, if we pass on personal data to a family company, we require that it protect such information in a manner that is consistent with this policy. If you want us to stop sharing your personal data among Carnegie-owned companies, please contact us.

If you provide your consent, we will share personal data with schools, colleges, and universities so they can provide you with information about their educational offerings. We maintain personal data for up to 10 years.

Additionally, with your consent, we may share the personal data you provide online with companies not affiliated with us (i.e. third-party companies) who are interested in marketing their products or services to you or in asking you questions, both online and offline. We will request to obtain your consent by an "opt-in" method, or by other means (such as sending to you an email). Companies with whom we might share your personal data may include consumer products, telecom, financial, military, market research, entertainment, and educational services companies and their third-party service providers. If you want us to stop sharing your personal data with these companies, please contact us. If you consent to receiving communications from non-affiliated companies, you may need to communicate with them directly if you later decide that you no longer wish to receive their communications or if you wish to change any data you provided online. In this instance, any changes or amendments to your personal data must be given directly to each company who communicates with you as these changes, amendments and/or deletions will not be exchanged between us and non-affiliated companies.

If we do share personal data with a non-affiliated company, to the extent practical, we require that they protect such information in a manner that is consistent with this policy. We cannot, however, guarantee how these non-affiliated companies will use your personal data.

## 7\. Personal Data Gathered Under Previous Versions of This Privacy Policy.

Personal data collected via the Site will generally be governed by the version of the Privacy Policy in effect at the time the information was gathered. We will not retroactively make material changes to the way we use personally identifiable information collected under previous versions of this Privacy Policy without obtaining your consent.

## 8\. Use and Disclosure of Anonymous Information.

We sometimes use the non-personal data that we collect to improve the design and content of the Site and to enable us to personalize your Internet experience. We also may use this information in the aggregate to analyze how the Site is used, as well as to offer you products, programs or services. Sometimes we share aggregate information with others, including affiliated companies and non-affiliated companies.

## 9\. Receipt of Communications; Withdrawal of Consent.

If you decide not to receive marketing or promotional emails from us that may relate, for example, to new services or offerings, you may withdraw your consent to receive these communications by clicking here to (i) deregister your account; or (ii) change or edit your preferences. You may also use the consent withdrawal mechanism that is contained in an email.

If you would like to withdraw your consent to receive marketing or promotional postal mail from us, please click here or let us know in writing via letter addressed to: Attn: Privacy Carnegie Dartlet LLC 151 W. 26th Street, 11th Floor New York, NY 10001. For all postal mail requests, please include your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. We cannot accept postal mail requests via telephone or facsimile, nor will we be responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly or lack complete information. Please note that we may require up to sixty (60) days to fully remove your postal mail information from our mailings.

Following your opt-out, please be aware that we, or our affiliates, may continue to contact you via email or postal mail for administrative purposes, including, but not limited to, follow-up messages regarding the administration of your account, any services, features or functions you remain affirmatively enrolled in or registered to use, any promotions or sweepstakes you have participated in or have entered, goods, services or products you have ordered or other transactions you have undertaken on the Site.

## 10\. Collection of Information By Others.

The Site may contain links to other websites, including links that are placed there by us, such as third-party advertisements or text hyperlinks. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of any other website. We encourage all users of the Site to be aware of when they leave the Site, and to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personal data. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by the Site, through the Site. We may offer additional email services or promotions that are sponsored by or co-sponsored with non-affiliated companies. Based on our agreement with them, these third parties may obtain personal data that site visitors voluntarily submit to participate in the contest, sweepstakes, or promotion. We have no control over the use of this information by these companies.

## 11\. Cookies.

To enhance your online experience with us, many of our web pages use "cookies." Cookies are text files placed on your hard disk by our web server to store your preferences. Cookies, by themselves, do not tell us your email address or other personal data unless you choose to provide this information to us. However, once you choose to provide the personal data, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer.

We use cookies as a convenience feature to save you time, to understand how the Site is used, and to improve the content and offerings on the Site. For example, we may use cookies to personalize your experience at our web pages or recall your specific information on subsequent visits (e.g. to recognize you by name when you return to the Site). We also may use cookies to offer you products, programs or services. You can opt to have your browser reject cookies. If you do that, you may need to re-register with us every time you visit the Site in order to participate in certain functions of the Site. You should also know that companies that advertise on the Site (and their agents) might use their own cookies. This policy does not cover how these companies use their cookies.

## 12\. Clickstream Data.

As you use the Internet, a trail of electronic information is left at each web site you visit. This information, which is sometimes referred to as "Clickstream Data," can be collected and stored by a web site's server. Clickstream Data can tell us the type of computer and browsing software you use and the address of the web site from which you linked to the Site. We may use Clickstream Data as a form of non-personal data to anonymously determine how much time visitors spend on each page of the Site, how visitors navigate throughout the Site and how we may tailor our web pages to better meet the needs of visitors. This information will only be used to improve the Site. Any collection or use of Clickstream Data will be anonymous and aggregate.

## 13\. Supplementing Information.

From time to time we may supplement information you give us with information from other sources, such as information validating your address. Thus, information we obtain through the Site may be intermingled with and used in conjunction with information obtained through sources other than the Site, including both offline and online sources.

## 14\. Discussions and Community Tools.

We may, from time to time, make review lists, chat rooms, forums, message boards, blogs, newsgroups and other community tools available to you. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information for other users to view and for us to use. For example, from time to time, we may use the content you write (including your name or screen name if you post it) for promotional purposes, in email newsletters or elsewhere, and by using the Site and/or these chat rooms, forums, message boards, news groups, and other community tools, you agree that we may do so. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal data in these areas, since anyone - not just us - may access your publicly posted information.

## 15\. Our Commitment to Security.

We believe we have in place the appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security and correctly use the information we collect online. Whenever personal data is passed on to non-affiliated companies, to the extent practical, we require that they also have in place the appropriate safeguards. We cannot, however, guarantee that they do so.

## 16\. California and International Users.

California Users.

Please refer to our specific "CA Privacy Policy" page.

International Users.

If you are visiting the Site from a location outside of the United States, your connection will be through and to servers located in the United States and all information you provide will be processed and securely maintained in our web servers and internal systems located within the United States. IN ADDITION, IF YOU ARE LOCATED OUTSIDE THE UNITED STATES, YOU SHOULD NOTE THAT YOUR INFORMATION WILL BE TRANSFERRED TO THE UNITED STATES, THE LAWS OF WHICH MAY BE DEEMED BY OTHER COUNTRIES TO HAVE INADEQUATE DATA PROTECTION (see, for example, EU General Data Protection Regulation, a copy of which can be found [here](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=uriserv:OJ.L_.2016.119.01.0001.01.ENG&toc=OJ:L:2016:119:TOC)). Users of the Site located in countries outside of the United States of America who submit personal data do thereby consent to the general use of such data as provided in this privacy policy and to the transfer of that information to and/or storage of the information in the United States of America. To the maximum extent allowable, this policy and our legal obligations are subject to the laws of the State of New York and the United States of America, regardless of the location of any user. If you are a European Union citizen or reside in the European Union you have the right to contact the applicable supervisory authority if you believe that your personal data is not being used or stored properly.

## 17\. How You Can Access or Correct Your Personal data.

You can access or correct your personal data by signing into your account and editing your profile. For instructions on how you can access the personal data that we have collected about you online, or how to correct any errors in such information, please contact us.

To protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to help verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

## 18\. Special Note for Parents.

We will not knowingly accept personal data from anyone under 16 years old in violation of applicable laws. If you believe that your child under 16 has gained access to the Site without your permission, please contact us. We have taken commercially reasonable steps to restrict use of the Site to those who are at least 16 years old. We do not market products or services for purchase by children and all products or services we market are for purchase by individuals over 16 years old only, or with adult permission.

## 19\. Transfer of Business Assets.

The personal data you provide is considered a company asset and may be included among transferred assets if the Site, we, or parent(s) or any of our subsidiaries or affiliates or any of our assets are ever acquired by a third party.

## 20\. Changes to this Policy.

Because our business needs may change over time, we reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this policy at any time. If at any time in the future we plan to use your personal data in a way that differs from this policy, we will revise this policy as appropriate. This policy is effective as of May 25, 2018. 

## 21\. How to Contact Us.

If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy or believe that we are not properly using or storing your personal data you may contact us or write to the following address: 

CollegeXpress  
c/o Carnegie Dartlet LLC  
210 Littleton Road, Suite 100  
Westford, MA 01886  
Attn: Privacy

Telephone: (978)692-5092  
Facsimile: (978)692-4174  
Email: [privacy@collegexpress.com](mailto:privacy@collegexpress.com)
